A Guide to the Hjalmar Hjorth Boyeson Collection
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #6903-c
Hjalmar Hjorth Boyeson Collection 1867-1895
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
6903-c
13 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Deposit [ 17 Dec 1963 ] 17 Aug 1965
Item Listing
- Letters
  - Thomas Worchester, [ Waltham, Massachusetts], to Hjalmar Hjorth Boyesen, [? Chicago], 1870 Jun 29; ALS, 1 p.
    [Forwards his letter to [Silas Tertius] Rand, treasurer "at that time"; sends Rand's answer; congratulates him on his marriage.]
  - Robert Scheffer, private secretary to Queen Elizabeth of Rumania, Buccarest, to Hjalmar Hjorth Boyesen, New York, 1888 Mar 8; ALS, 2 p.
    [Acknowledges for the queen the receipt some time ago of
    Idyls of Norway and Other Poems
    and
    Queen Titania
    which she greatly enjoyed; lets him know he impressed the queen with his account of Carmen Sylva's work in
    The Independent
    . ]
  - Seth Low, Mayor of Brooklyn, to Hjalmar Hjorth Boyesen, New York, 1889 Oct 10; TLS, 1 p.
    [Acknowledges letter; hopes that his optimism in regard to Columbia [University] is not tinged by his views on immigration; invites him to his house.]
  - John Bach McMaster, University of Pennsylvania, to Hjalmar Hjorth Boyesen, New York, 1889 Oct 14; TLS, 2 p.
    [Apologizes for his shortcomings; offers an apology to the "Executive Council"; encloses money to cover his debt.]
  - John W. Lovell, New York, to Hjalmar Hjorth Boyesen, New York City, 1890 Sep 25; TLS, 1 p.
    [Sends him the London address of publisher Charles Wolcott Balestier; discusses the publishing of Boyesen's next book.]
  - John W. Lovell, United States Book Company, New York, to Hjalmar Hjorth Boyesen, New York City, 1891 Apr 20; TL (initialed), 1 p.
    [Discusses the correction of proofs; says the company does not object to the use of the story in German in
    The New York Staatszeitung
  - John W. Lovell, United States Book Company, New York, to Hjalmar Hjorth Boyesen, New York City, 1891 Apr 22; TL (initialed), 1 p.
    [Discusses proofs; says Charles Wolcott Balestier will receive his letter upon his return from England tomorrow.]
  - John W. Lovell, United States Book Company, New York, to Hjalmar Hjorth Boyesen, New York City, 1891 Apr 29; TL (initialed), 1 p.
    [Discusses pages missing from proofs; says that Charles Wolcott Balestier will meet with him upon his return from Boston. ]
  - A. D. Hurd, United States Book Company, New York, to Hjalmar Hjorth Boyesen, New York City, 1891 May 16; TLS, 1 p.
    [Says that plate corrections have been sent to the printer, the price for the requested 250 copies of the
    Mammon of Unrighteousness
    in sheets, folded and collated, would be 24 cents per copy.]
  - Michael Augustine Corrigan, New York, to Hjalmar Hjorth Boyesen, New York, 1893 Nov 16; ALS, 1 p.
    [Refers to the
    New York Herald
    of that day; asks what proof he has to assert that he is in league with Tammany Hall and in control of Richard Croker's conscience; wants him to retract these charges.]
  - Michael Augustine Corrigan, New York, Archbishop's House, to Hjalmar Hjorth Boyesen, New York City, 1893 Nov 17; ALS, 1 p.
    [Appreciates compliance with his request; looks forward to Boyesen's visit next Tuesday evening.]
  - Annie Sheldon Coombs, New York, to Hjalmar Hjorth Boyesen, New York, n.y. Apr 2; ALS, 4 p.
    [Thanks him for letter of reassurance, which revived her hopes for success; says she is upset about her own low opinion of herself.]
  - Minnie V. D. Ripley, New York, to Hjalmar Hjorth Boyesen, New York, n.y. Apr 3; ALS, 2 p.
    [Thanks him for the charming souvenir; says the inscription went right to her heart.]
  - [ Julie Grinnell Cruger], New York, to Hjalmar Hjorth Boyesen, [ New York], n.y. Aug 22; ALS, 3 p.
    [Refers to two letters she has written him; says she is bored with the subject of "rich woman," which has been "done to death in newspapers and fiction"; feels sorry that "Rebellious Daughters" has not been liked and says she will let the other magazine have it if they want it; says that editors love the public as an imbecile; thinks the public is fairly intelligent; expresses admiration for Boyesen's father.]
  - Julie Grinnel Cruger, [ New York], to Hjalmar Hjorth Boyesen, [ New York], n. d.; ALS, 3 p.
    [Thanks him for a book; marvels at his use of English; says she will always remember how he encouraged her.]
- Miscellaneous
  - Proof to preface Hjalmar Hjorth Boyesen's Mammon of Unrighteousness, 1891 May; Proof, 2 p.